<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Rethinking Value-Added Taxes for Developing Economies</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-vat-has-failed-developing-economies-by-rabah-arezki-et-al-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/how-vat-has-failed-developing-economies-by-rabah-arezki-et-al-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For decades, the VAT has been a cornerstone of tax systems worldwide, providing governments with a stable source of revenue and fiscal flexibility. But in many countries, it has not replaced lost tariff income and has encouraged exports of raw materials, highlighting the need to align tax policy with national development priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:45:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Green Shipping Could Mean a Green Africa</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/revenue-from-price-on-shipping-emissions-should-support-africa-green-growth-by-chukwumerije-okereke-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/revenue-from-price-on-shipping-emissions-should-support-africa-green-growth-by-chukwumerije-okereke-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the International Maritime Organization gathers to adopt its Net-Zero Framework, which includes a binding emissions-pricing mechanism, it must begin thinking about how to distribute the resulting revenues equitably. Ideally, the funds would be used to unlock Africa’s green-energy potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:35:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Paradigm Shift on Animal Testing</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fda-and-nih-move-to-phase-out-animal-testing-by-peter-singer-and-sankalpa-ghose-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fda-and-nih-move-to-phase-out-animal-testing-by-peter-singer-and-sankalpa-ghose-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Since the 1938 Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, the US has required animal testing to predict human outcomes for all drug, therapy, cosmetic, and food safety reviews and approvals. But the authorities are finally acknowledging what industry leaders have long known: animal testing is cruel, costly, and ineffective.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:17:26 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s “Warrior” Ethos Won't Protect Europe</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-not-trust-trump-to-safeguard-its-security-by-ana-palacio-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/europe-must-not-trust-trump-to-safeguard-its-security-by-ana-palacio-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the Trump administration, “America First” is no mere slogan; it is a policy ethos that justifies inward-looking, capricious, and transactional approaches with no basis in rules, norms, or values. While many countries are adjusting to this new strategic reality, the EU's response leaves much to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:29:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The World Must Not Ignore Israel’s Attacks on Gaza’s Hospitals</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/world-cannot-ignore-israel-attacks-on-gaza-hospitals-by-tushara-surapaneni-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/world-cannot-ignore-israel-attacks-on-gaza-hospitals-by-tushara-surapaneni-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last two years, the Israeli government has repeatedly violated international humanitarian law, particularly in its systematic attacks on Gaza’s medical facilities and personnel. To uphold the rules of war, the UN Security Council should adopt a resolution that highlights attacks on health-care infrastructure globally.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:55:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Forbidden Jokes</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/jimmy-kimmel-donald-trump-attack-on-free-speech-by-ian-buruma-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/jimmy-kimmel-donald-trump-attack-on-free-speech-by-ian-buruma-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last month, ABC suspended late-night talk show host Jimmy Kimmel – a frequent critic of US President Donald Trump – after pressure from the government. While Kimmel was reinstated, Trump will likely continue to threaten comedians, because nothing is more damaging to a demagogue than being laughed at.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:52:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin’s Polycrisis</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/west-must-accelerate-sanctions-to-stop-putin-war-machine-by-sergei-guriev-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/west-must-accelerate-sanctions-to-stop-putin-war-machine-by-sergei-guriev-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite mounting economic and demographic pressures, Russian President Vladimir Putin will continue to feed the war machine so long as he gains ground in Ukraine. To change his calculus, Western leaders must strengthen sanctions against the Kremlin, provide advanced weapons to Ukraine, and incentivize Russian brain drain.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:02:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blaming Russia Won’t Stop the Populist Right</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/russia-not-behind-popular-support-for-right-wing-parties-by-maciej-kisilowski-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/russia-not-behind-popular-support-for-right-wing-parties-by-maciej-kisilowski-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Russian meddling and disinformation have been an important subtext of recent European elections in Moldova and the Czech Republic, as well as in earlier elections where right-wing populists have done well. But fixation on the Kremlin obscures a deeper, more troubling reality: the genuine popular appeal of right-wing ideology.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:20:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Total Victory in Gaza Is a Delusion</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/israel-military-victory-in-gaza-will-amount-to-a-moral-defeat-and-lead-to-eternal-conflict-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/israel-military-victory-in-gaza-will-amount-to-a-moral-defeat-and-lead-to-eternal-conflict-by-shlomo-ben-ami-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Even if Hamas is ultimately “defeated" in Gaza, the blow it has dealt to Israel amounts to a psychological victory that will remain etched in the collective memory of the Palestinian people. Conversely, an Israeli military “victory” would imply a staggering moral and strategic defeat.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Total Lawfare</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-lawfare-invites-comparisons-to-hitler-and-1930s-by-michael-burleigh-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-lawfare-invites-comparisons-to-hitler-and-1930s-by-michael-burleigh-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump's unrestrained and unscrupulous use of the US state to punish his enemies has naturally invited more comparisons to Adolf Hitler. But the more pressing question now is not whether Trump is a fascist; it is whether those with any economic or political power will collaborate or resist.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:33:09 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Federal Reserve’s Other Problem</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-regulators-proposal-would-increase-risk-of-financial-crisis-by-simon-johnson-and-corey-klemmer-1-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-regulators-proposal-would-increase-risk-of-financial-crisis-by-simon-johnson-and-corey-klemmer-1-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;How much bank leverage –&amp;nbsp;debt relative to equity – is good for the economy, and how much leverage jeopardizes the stability of the financial system? This summer, the relevant US regulators decided to reopen that debate with a shoddily prepared proposal that has "financial crisis risk" written all over it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:47:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Supreme Court Unleashed Trump’s War on the States</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/supreme-court-unleashed-trump-ice-national-guard-crackdowns-by-aziz-huq-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/supreme-court-unleashed-trump-ice-national-guard-crackdowns-by-aziz-huq-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration's militarization of US cities – apparently selected because of their partisan divergence from the White House – represents a failure of federalism. While Congress's abdication of its constitutional duties is well known, the Supreme Court has joined it in greenlighting executive overreach.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:40:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Ethical Supply Chains Survive the Tariff Storm?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariffs-supply-chain-volatility-favors-companies-with-responsible-purchasing-commitments-by-joleen-ong-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/tariffs-supply-chain-volatility-favors-companies-with-responsible-purchasing-commitments-by-joleen-ong-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As trade-related costs persist, fashion and apparel industry leaders must shift their mindset. Their businesses’ resilience will not come from diplomacy or presidential handshakes, but from trust-based relationships built on fair purchasing practices, sustainability concerns, and other ethical commitments.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:51:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Much Financial Speculation Can the Real Economy Withstand?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rampant-speculation-could-set-the-stage-for-another-2008-style-crisis-by-dambisa-moyo-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rampant-speculation-could-set-the-stage-for-another-2008-style-crisis-by-dambisa-moyo-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fueled by mobile-trading apps, deregulation, and social media, short-term speculation is reshaping financial markets and eroding the patient capital on which businesses have long relied. If left unchecked, this frenzy could destabilize the US economy and set the stage for a 2008-style global crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:11:15 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>As Growth Decouples From Employment, the Fed Faces a Trilemma</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-financial-stability-concerns-as-growth-decouples-from-employment-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/fed-financial-stability-concerns-as-growth-decouples-from-employment-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With equity markets reaching new heights, the market’s expectation that the US Federal Reserve will cut rates to head off a labor-market slowdown is itself creating a policy challenge for the central bank. In addition to its explicit dual mandate, the Fed now must also worry about financial stability.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Democrats Can “Win” the US Government Shutdown</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-government-shutdown-how-democrats-can-confront-trump-by-jan-werner-mueller-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-government-shutdown-how-democrats-can-confront-trump-by-jan-werner-mueller-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To prevail against a would-be autocrat, US Democrats should make an argument about democracy. Not only has a Republican-controlled government closed, but the Republican-controlled Congress is simply handing power to an executive who has signaled clearly his intention to act illegally and unconstitutionally.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:21:47 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Mayors Need to Lead</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/equipping-mayors-local-leaders-key-to-effective-governance-by-steve-rotheram-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/equipping-mayors-local-leaders-key-to-effective-governance-by-steve-rotheram-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As power in the United Kingdom continues to shift from London to the rest of the country, and as the European Union looks to city governments to drive an economic recovery and more, people across the continent will increasingly be counting on local leaders. The task now is to make sure those leaders are equipped for the task.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:04:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>India’s Strategic Balancing Act</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-thaw-with-china-and-chill-with-the-us-not-what-they-seem-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/india-thaw-with-china-and-chill-with-the-us-not-what-they-seem-by-shashi-tharoor-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Strategic autonomy is not about oscillating between poles, but about preventing one's own agenda from being subsumed by that of another power. For India today, this means preventing escalation with China without succumbing to the illusion of partnership, and negotiating firmly with the US without disrupting constructive engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:00:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Africa’s Rare-Earth Opportunity</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-critical-mineral-deals-must-not-perpetuate-the-resource-curse-by-kingsley-moghalu-2025-10</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-critical-mineral-deals-must-not-perpetuate-the-resource-curse-by-kingsley-moghalu-2025-10</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As global demand for critical minerals surges, Africa has a once-in-a-century opportunity to break the “resource curse” and convert its vast natural wealth into economic and social transformation. But, to seize it, the continent’s leaders must avoid falling into old traps.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:00:52 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The UN Without America</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-un-without-america</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/the-un-without-america</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Though multilateralism remains as important as ever to defend human rights, support peace and security, and deliver cooperative solutions to shared problems, the 80th session of the United Nations General Assembly painted a bleak picture of the institution’s prospects. To avoid fading into irrelevance, the UN must transform itself – including by radically reducing its dependence on the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 12:07:52 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>