<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Putin Challenged Trump in Poland</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-drone-attack-in-poland-intended-to-test-trump-by-slawomir-sierakowski-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-drone-attack-in-poland-intended-to-test-trump-by-slawomir-sierakowski-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin followed his red-carpet summit with Donald Trump in Alaska by escalating attacks on Ukraine and provocations on NATO's eastern flank. Unless Trump responds adequately to the incursion of Russian combat drones in Poland, it will signal to Putin that he can humiliate the US president with impunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:57:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yes, the World Free Rides on America</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/american-economy-europe-and-many-others-free-riders-by-todd-g-buchholz-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/american-economy-europe-and-many-others-free-riders-by-todd-g-buchholz-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Like it or not, Europe, and a good part of the wider world, has been a free rider, hitching its wagon to the US cowboy economy. This is true not only in the familiar area of defense and security, but also in energy, pharmaceuticals, aerospace, and other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Powell’s Last Chance to Protect the Fed</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/powell-reforms-could-spare-fed-further-damage-in-final-months-of-term-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/powell-reforms-could-spare-fed-further-damage-in-final-months-of-term-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although the outgoing chair of the US Federal Reserve cannot correct for the institution's biggest recent policy mistakes, he can, and should, address other failures that are equally important for the economy. After all, there is a broad consensus that reforms are urgently needed to salvage the Fed’s effectiveness and credibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Von der Leyen’s Breaking Point</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/von-der-leyen-state-of-the-union-reflects-a-dynamic-that-has-become-untenable-by-alberto-alemanno-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/von-der-leyen-state-of-the-union-reflects-a-dynamic-that-has-become-untenable-by-alberto-alemanno-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen's ability to respond to the concerns of ordinary Europeans has long been constrained by member governments, which are happy to blame “Brussels” for the lack of progress. This dynamic is untenable, but to break it, von der Leyen will have to risk her own political capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:25:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Violence As Policy in Trump’s America</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/right-wing-reaction-to-kirk-murder-stoke-more-violence-by-jan-werner-mueller-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/right-wing-reaction-to-kirk-murder-stoke-more-violence-by-jan-werner-mueller-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Both Republicans and Democrats have been victims of violent attacks this year, but the murder of the right-wing activist Charlie Kirk has once again highlighted the fundamental asymmetry of contemporary American politics. Unlike the Democrats and most Americans, many leaders on the right view their supporters' violence as legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 11:01:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Should Africa Respond to Trump’s Tariffs?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-must-forge-united-front-against-us-bilateralism-by-shimukunku-manchishi-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/africa-must-forge-united-front-against-us-bilateralism-by-shimukunku-manchishi-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s sweeping tariffs are hitting African exporters hard, jeopardizing growth and regional stability. To avoid being sidelined in a fragmented global trading landscape, African governments must bargain collectively to negotiate deals with the US and strengthen ties with other emerging powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:09:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflationary Tales</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/why-we-need-a-new-inflation-playbook-by-jonathan-levy-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/why-we-need-a-new-inflation-playbook-by-jonathan-levy-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The inflationary surge of the 1970s has long served as a cautionary tale, and that episode has shaped how central banks have carried out their mandates ever since. Two recent books revisit the standard narrative about that period in light of the 2021–23 inflation, offering sharply contrasting lessons for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:08:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Trump a State Capitalist?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/is-trump-a-state-capitalist</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/is-trump-a-state-capitalist</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;While US President Donald Trump has embraced some elements of the free-market doctrine that dominated economic policymaking over the past half-century, he has also pursued an unprecedented level of state intervention. With Trump’s “pay-to-play” approach to economic management seeming to&amp;nbsp;combine the worst of both worlds, we asked &lt;em&gt;PS &lt;/em&gt;commentators how it might transform American capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 09:25:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Twilight of Pax Americana</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-tariffs-ignore-economic-realities-and-destroy-us-global-leadership-by-koichi-hamada-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-tariffs-ignore-economic-realities-and-destroy-us-global-leadership-by-koichi-hamada-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If Donald Trump continues to wield the threat of higher tariffs, he might be able to claim a few more “victories,” in the form of exploitative trade deals with longtime US allies and partners. But the costs of ignoring basic economic realities will be high, and US global leadership may never recover.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 15:23:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Globalization Is Dead, but Planetarization Has Yet to Be Born</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/globalization-dead-and-military-spending-far-outstripping-climate-investment-by-bertrand-badre-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/globalization-dead-and-military-spending-far-outstripping-climate-investment-by-bertrand-badre-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Future historians (if there are any) will wonder why, in the mid-2020s, humans poured unprecedented resources into preparing to fight each other, while neglecting collective action against obvious planetary threats. If there is to be any hope of survival, a new mindset must take hold.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 13:51:11 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel’s Doha Strike Has Destroyed American Credibility</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/israel-doha-qatar-strike-end-of-us-credibility-by-daoud-kuttab-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/israel-doha-qatar-strike-end-of-us-credibility-by-daoud-kuttab-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After decades of enjoying impunity for its violations of international law and norms, Israel no longer even hesitates to do whatever it wants. Aside from the individual victims of the attack on Hamas negotiators in Qatar, the main casualty of Israel’s escalation is US credibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is a French Sovereign-Debt Crisis Looming?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/france-sovereign-debt-crisis-will-cause-market-turmoil-before-ecb-intervention-by-desmond-lachman-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/france-sovereign-debt-crisis-will-cause-market-turmoil-before-ecb-intervention-by-desmond-lachman-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It is highly likely that the European Central Bank will have to intervene to prop up France's economy. But this lending will almost certainly have conditions attached, which the French political class will probably not accept until they are staring down the barrel of a government-bond-market collapse.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:59:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Tariffs Will Widen the North-South Divide</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-disproportionately-hurt-developing-economies-by-qiyuan-xu-and-yutao-huang-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-reciprocal-tariffs-disproportionately-hurt-developing-economies-by-qiyuan-xu-and-yutao-huang-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;An analysis of US President Donald Trump's "reciprocal" tariffs reveals a stark conclusion: the lower a country’s income, the higher the tariff burden it is likely to bear. In this sense, the tariffs almost seem to be deliberately designed to impede development and exacerbate global inequalities.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:01:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fighting Poverty Must Not Stop</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/innnovative-finance-could-hold-key-to-lifting-millions-out-of-poverty-by-akinwumi-a-adesina-and-ilan-goldfajn-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/innnovative-finance-could-hold-key-to-lifting-millions-out-of-poverty-by-akinwumi-a-adesina-and-ilan-goldfajn-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Reducing poverty fuels growth, bolsters resilience, and fosters stability, making it essential to long-term development. Even amid economic slowdowns and strained public budgets, governments must double down on human capital and infrastructure investments through well-designed, cost-effective strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:26:16 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Science Isn’t a Luxury for Developing Countries</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/low-and-middle-income-countries-must-invest-in-basic-research-by-bridget-boakye-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/low-and-middle-income-countries-must-invest-in-basic-research-by-bridget-boakye-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the COVID-19 pandemic to intensifying climate shocks, a series of crises has exposed the risks of depending on wealthy countries to deliver scientific and technological solutions. If developing economies are to respond effectively to crises and take control of their development, they must build their own research ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 15:18:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>For Whom the Ukrainian Bell Tolls</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-running-out-of-soldiers-needs-foreign-volunteers-by-anna-husarska-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/ukraine-running-out-of-soldiers-needs-foreign-volunteers-by-anna-husarska-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With Vladimir Putin apparently willing to shrug off any number of losses, one must assume that Russia will be able to sustain a grinding war of attrition for as long as it takes to deplete Ukraine’s ranks. That is why supporting Ukraine now requires finding ways to get more foreign volunteers to join the fight.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:21:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A New Economics for Neglected Places</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/new-economics-neglected-places-by-paul-collier</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/new-economics-neglected-places-by-paul-collier</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In rich and poor countries alike, when left-behind regions are hit by an adverse shock, they will spiral down unless the shock is mitigated by supportive and timely finance guided by local contextual knowledge. That is the clear lesson from successful cases of economic renewal over the past half-century.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Global Trade Is Winning Trump’s War On It</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-tariffs-will-have-only-a-moderate-impact-on-trade-by-daniel-gros-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-tariffs-will-have-only-a-moderate-impact-on-trade-by-daniel-gros-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Since returning to the White House, Donald Trump has repeatedly introduced, paused, reversed, and hiked tariffs, often to unprecedented levels, raising fears about the future of the global trading system. But the average effective tariff rate that the US has applied remains much lower than Trump's pronouncements would suggest.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:37:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s “Trump” Card</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinas-trump-card-benefiting-from-us-unreliability-by-ian-bremmer-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinas-trump-card-benefiting-from-us-unreliability-by-ian-bremmer-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Faced with an unreliable administration in the United States, many countries are now seeking alternatives to reduce their long-term exposure to US policymaking. China has taken note and is billing itself as a steady hand that remains committed to multilateralism, long-term deals, and “non-interference.”&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:02:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Are Financial Markets Shrugging at Trump’s War on the Fed?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/disconnect-between-threat-to-fed-and-investors-reaction-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/disconnect-between-threat-to-fed-and-investors-reaction-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Few laws of economics are better established than the proposition that central banks independent from politics do a better job of implementing monetary policy. So why are financial markets responding to Donald Trump's attacks on the US Federal Reserve so calmly?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>