<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>Is Brazil’s Democracy Out of the Woods?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-brazilian-democracy-safe-after-bolsonaro-sentencing-by-sergio-fausto-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/is-brazilian-democracy-safe-after-bolsonaro-sentencing-by-sergio-fausto-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The conviction of former President Jair Bolsonaro for launching a coup will once again test the resilience of Brazilian democracy. Much will depend on whether Brazil's traditional conservatives continue to ally with the far right, as they did during Bolsonaro's presidency.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:47:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Seemingly Conscious AI Is Coming</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/seemingly-conscious-ai-urgent-threat-tech-industry-must-address-by-mustafa-suleyman-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/seemingly-conscious-ai-urgent-threat-tech-industry-must-address-by-mustafa-suleyman-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Debates about whether AI truly can be conscious are a distraction. What matters in the near term is the perception that they are – and why the temptation to design AI systems that foster this perception must be resisted.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:20:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The US Will Rue Trump’s Trade War on India</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-will-regret-trump-tariffs-on-india-by-duvvuri-subbarao-1-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/america-will-regret-trump-tariffs-on-india-by-duvvuri-subbarao-1-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Indian economy will feel significant short-term pain from the steep tariffs imposed by US President Donald Trump. But India will adapt and emerge more resilient, while the US is jeopardizing its own long-term economic and geopolitical interests by alienating a rising trade partner and encouraging alternatives to the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:01:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lower Interest Rates Are the Right Policy for the Wrong Reasons</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rate-cuts-right-policy-but-could-signal-loss-of-fed-independence-by-mark-blyth-and-nicolo-fraccaroli-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/rate-cuts-right-policy-but-could-signal-loss-of-fed-independence-by-mark-blyth-and-nicolo-fraccaroli-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There is strong evidence to support the case for interest-rate cuts in the United States, given the disproportionate impact of higher rates on the most vulnerable. Yet with Donald Trump loudly demanding that the US Federal Reserve lower borrowing costs, the situation has become more complicated than it needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 09:11:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Migration Is the Key to Global Prosperity</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/migration-key-to-shared-prosperity-wealthy-and-developing-countries-alike-by-carlos-alvarado-quesada-and-katrina-burgess-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/migration-key-to-shared-prosperity-wealthy-and-developing-countries-alike-by-carlos-alvarado-quesada-and-katrina-burgess-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In many democracies nowadays, migration is discussed in visceral, emotional terms that bear little resemblance to reality. If that does not change, the future costs of mismanaging the issue will fall on everyone – not least the world's aging, fiscally strained democracies.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The False Promise of “AI for Social Good”</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/ai-for-social-good-false-promise-of-technosolutionism-by-abeba-birhane-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/ai-for-social-good-false-promise-of-technosolutionism-by-abeba-birhane-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In peddling "AI for Social Good" initiatives, technology companies and philanthropies are suggesting that complex political, historical, and social issues can be reduced to technical problems. But given how today's AI systems work, there is no reason we should believe them – and much reason to be suspicious of their claims.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A New Multilateralism for the SDGs</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/achieving-sdgs-requires-a-new-form-of-multilateralism-by-sakiko-fukuda-parr-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/achieving-sdgs-requires-a-new-form-of-multilateralism-by-sakiko-fukuda-parr-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The odds of reforming the multilateral system – which currently serves a few narrow interests – remain slim amid rising geopolitical tensions and growing populist sentiment in rich countries. To make progress on the Sustainable Development Goals, a more diverse group of actors must devise ways to circumvent systemic barriers.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fulfilling the Promise of Private Development Finance</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/derisk-investment-in-sustainable-development-to-mobilize-private-finance-at-scale-by-homi-kharas-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/derisk-investment-in-sustainable-development-to-mobilize-private-finance-at-scale-by-homi-kharas-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Private development finance was supposed to be a game-changer for sustainable development, but it has so far fallen short of expectations. But the recent proliferation of initiatives and alliances focused on de-risking such investments suggests that this might be about to change.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How Trade Fuels Illicit Financial Flows from Developing Countries</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/regulate-open-account-trade-to-reduce-illicit-financial-flows-by-yuefen-li-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/regulate-open-account-trade-to-reduce-illicit-financial-flows-by-yuefen-li-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Trade has become a favored channel for those engaged in illicit or criminal activities because 80-85% of it is conducted via open-account trade, a bilateral transaction in which “goods are shipped and delivered before payment is due.” Addressing the issue won't be easy, but solutions exist.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South-South Is the Way to Global Financial Reform</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/south-south-collaboration-offers-model-for-development-finance-by-hannah-wanjie-ryder-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/south-south-collaboration-offers-model-for-development-finance-by-hannah-wanjie-ryder-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite all the talk of reforming the global financial architecture to address development needs across the Global South, little progress will be made without a fundamental change in perspective. After all, the problem with the current system is that it disregards the conditions most developing countries face.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Ocean Is the Next Geopolitical Battleground</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/oceans-next-geopolitical-battleground-by-maria-jose-valverde-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/oceans-next-geopolitical-battleground-by-maria-jose-valverde-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The world’s maritime regions are hotter, more contested, and more fragile than ever before. As climate disruption collides with strategic competition, the ocean is re-emerging as a critical frontier in global geopolitics.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Will COP30 Deliver?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/cop30-what-would-make-the-conference-a-success-by-maria-fernanda-espinosa-et-al-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/cop30-what-would-make-the-conference-a-success-by-maria-fernanda-espinosa-et-al-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With multilateralism under strain from geopolitical rivalries and global economic fragmentation, the Brazilian hosts of this year's United Nations Climate Change Conference have a big challenge on their hands. But, of course, whether they can pull off a successful COP depends on how one defines success.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A New Economics for Neglected Places</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/new-economics-neglected-places-by-paul-collier</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/new-economics-neglected-places-by-paul-collier</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In rich and poor countries alike, when left-behind regions are hit by an adverse shock, they will spiral down unless the shock is mitigated by supportive and timely finance guided by local contextual knowledge. That is the clear lesson from successful cases of economic renewal over the past half-century.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Latin America’s Big, Green Opportunity</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/latin-america-green-industrialization-best-and-only-path-by-laura-carvalho-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/latin-america-green-industrialization-best-and-only-path-by-laura-carvalho-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although the United States has abandoned climate leadership, the rest of the world is staying the course, and that gives Latin America a major strategic opportunity. The region has all the ingredients to become the low-carbon juggernaut that the world needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Eurasia’s Shifting Strategic Paradigm</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/central-asian-countries-geopolitical-balancing-act-by-nargis-kassenova-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/central-asian-countries-geopolitical-balancing-act-by-nargis-kassenova-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a region historically shaped by the push and pull of rival powers, Central Asian countries have sought to maintain geopolitical balance by cultivating strategic alliances with multiple global players. But Russia’s war against Ukraine and Donald Trump’s return to the White House are now putting that approach to the test.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sustainable Development Begins at School</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/what-it-will-take-to-achieve-sdg4-universal-education-by-kailash-satyarthi-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/what-it-will-take-to-achieve-sdg4-universal-education-by-kailash-satyarthi-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A sustainable future requires citizens with the skills and motivation to tackle structural, institutional, and systemic injustices. Universal access to education is essential, but education can be a powerful liberator, tool for inclusion, and source of opportunity only if it has compassion at its core.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unsustainable Development Goals?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/unsustainable-development-goals-by-ngaire-woods-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/magazine/unsustainable-development-goals-by-ngaire-woods-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a challenging global economic and geopolitical environment, achieving the Sustainable Development Goals will be possible only if the world makes the most of every multilateral development dollar. And a growing body of evidence indicates that that may mean giving those dollars directly to those who need them.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin Challenged Trump in Poland</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-drone-attack-in-poland-intended-to-test-trump-by-slawomir-sierakowski-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/putin-drone-attack-in-poland-intended-to-test-trump-by-slawomir-sierakowski-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin followed his red-carpet summit with Donald Trump in Alaska by escalating attacks on Ukraine and provocations on NATO's eastern flank. Unless Trump responds adequately to the incursion of Russian combat drones in Poland, it will signal to Putin that he can humiliate the US president with impunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:57:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Yes, the World Free Rides on America</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/american-economy-europe-and-many-others-free-riders-by-todd-g-buchholz-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/american-economy-europe-and-many-others-free-riders-by-todd-g-buchholz-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Like it or not, Europe, and a good part of the wider world, has been a free rider, hitching its wagon to the US cowboy economy. This is true not only in the familiar area of defense and security, but also in energy, pharmaceuticals, aerospace, and other sectors.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Powell’s Last Chance to Protect the Fed</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/powell-reforms-could-spare-fed-further-damage-in-final-months-of-term-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/powell-reforms-could-spare-fed-further-damage-in-final-months-of-term-by-mohamed-a-el-erian-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Although the outgoing chair of the US Federal Reserve cannot correct for the institution's biggest recent policy mistakes, he can, and should, address other failures that are equally important for the economy. After all, there is a broad consensus that reforms are urgently needed to salvage the Fed’s effectiveness and credibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 15:34:55 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>