<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Project Syndicate Archive Feed</title><link>https://www.project-syndicate.org/</link><description>Combined feed with archive links</description><item><title>China's “Trump” Card</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinas-trump-card-benefiting-from-us-unreliability-by-ian-bremmer-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/chinas-trump-card-benefiting-from-us-unreliability-by-ian-bremmer-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Faced with an unreliable administration in the United States, many countries are now seeking alternatives to reduce their long-term exposure to US policymaking. China has taken note and is billing itself as a steady hand that remains committed to multilateralism, long-term deals, and “non-interference.”&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:02:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Are Financial Markets Shrugging at Trump’s War on the Fed?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/disconnect-between-threat-to-fed-and-investors-reaction-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/disconnect-between-threat-to-fed-and-investors-reaction-by-barry-eichengreen-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Few laws of economics are better established than the proposition that central banks independent from politics do a better job of implementing monetary policy. So why are financial markets responding to Donald Trump's attacks on the US Federal Reserve so calmly?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:11:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>France’s Manufactured Debt and Government Drama</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/exaggerating-fiscal-risk-french-government-breeds-resistance-to-adjustment-by-jean-pierre-landau-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/exaggerating-fiscal-risk-french-government-breeds-resistance-to-adjustment-by-jean-pierre-landau-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;French Prime Minister François Bayrou’s government collapsed following a parliamentary confidence vote, and it has only itself to blame. In fact, there is good reason to think that citizens are overwhelmingly rejecting the government's budget precisely because they have effectively been told that they cannot.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The US Tightens the Dollar’s Death Grip on Brazilian Democracy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-sanctions-on-brazilian-judge-highlight-need-for-dollar-alternatives-by-camila-villard-duran-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/trump-administration-sanctions-on-brazilian-judge-highlight-need-for-dollar-alternatives-by-camila-villard-duran-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By imposing sanctions on Brazilian Supreme Court Justice Alexandre de Moraes, US President Donald Trump’s administration has launched an unprecedented assault on Brazil’s judicial independence. The move also underscores how the dollar’s global primacy undermines other countries’ sovereignty.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 11:41:51 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Who Will Model Democracy Now?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democracy-role-models-no-longer-us-europe-by-dani-rodrik-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/democracy-role-models-no-longer-us-europe-by-dani-rodrik-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Not so long ago, people around the world could look to Europe and America to see that economic growth, social justice, and political freedom are not only compatible but mutually reinforcing. While authoritarianism is on the rise in both places, one can find democratic role models elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 10:09:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Is Europe So Wimpy?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-is-europe-unable-to-project-strength-by-andres-velasco-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-is-europe-unable-to-project-strength-by-andres-velasco-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Trump's rogue America threatening from one side, Vladimir Putin's Russia from the other, and China becoming increasingly authoritarian, Europeans can no longer afford their leaders’ passivity. And democrats everywhere are also waiting for the world's only remaining good guy to step up.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 16:02:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indonesian Democracy on the Brink</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/indonesia-at-a-crossroads-by-lili-yan-ing-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/indonesia-at-a-crossroads-by-lili-yan-ing-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The protests currently sweeping Indonesia are not fleeting outbursts, but rather the culmination of long-suppressed grievances over abuses of power and the erosion of constitutional norms. To address this widespread discontent, President Prabowo Subianto must focus on four priorities.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:06:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>A Meaningful Last Gift for All Sentient Beings</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/terminally-ill-patients-contribute-to-medical-research-by-peter-singer-and-benjamin-l-sievers-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/terminally-ill-patients-contribute-to-medical-research-by-peter-singer-and-benjamin-l-sievers-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A new program in California offers terminally ill patients the chance to donate their bodies to medical research while still alive. These patients are contributing to the development of safer drugs for curing human diseases while helping to reduce the use of animals in research and adding meaning to their last days.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:46:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Europe Must Use Its Economic “Bazooka” Against the US</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-must-use-trade-bazooka-anti-coercion-instrument-against-trump-by-moreno-bertoldi-and-marco-buti-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/eu-must-use-trade-bazooka-anti-coercion-instrument-against-trump-by-moreno-bertoldi-and-marco-buti-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing is ever final with US President Donald Trump, who recently threatened new tariffs against the European Union and its member states for their digital regulations and taxes. The EU must finally stand up for itself by activating its most powerful tool against economic pressure, the Anti-Coercion Instrument.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 12:22:42 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Are Markets Ignoring the Obvious About America?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-markets-remain-calm-despite-trump-turmoil-by-erin-lockwood-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/why-markets-remain-calm-despite-trump-turmoil-by-erin-lockwood-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Given that Donald Trump’s agenda should concern those who hold capital, many are wondering why there has been so little resistance to his administration from markets and Big Business. Six possible explanations stand out – and none of them bodes well for the long term.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 09:59:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>How America Could Lead the Next Era of Digital Innovation</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-big-tech-monopolies-call-for-open-app-markets-act-by-gene-burrus-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-big-tech-monopolies-call-for-open-app-markets-act-by-gene-burrus-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the gatekeepers for the mobile app market, Apple and Google have amassed significant, persistent market power with which to extract monopoly rents from consumers and business users. The sooner that lawmakers and regulators address these barriers to competition (and thus innovation), the better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 08:41:06 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Genocide Being Redefined to Indict Israel?</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/israel-gaza-crime-of-genocide-being-redefined-by-konstanty-gebert-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/israel-gaza-crime-of-genocide-being-redefined-by-konstanty-gebert-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Given that the academic consensus on genocide recognizes only a handful of cases, it would be quite shocking for Israel – a country born from the ashes of the Holocaust – to be found guilty of the "crime of all crimes." Yet by massaging the meaning of the term, that is precisely what its critics are seeking to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bolsonaro and Trump Have Revealed the Biggest Threat to Democracy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/diverging-fates-of-bolsonaro-and-trump-by-pedro-abramovay-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/diverging-fates-of-bolsonaro-and-trump-by-pedro-abramovay-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump and former Brazilian President Jair Bolsonaro are emblematic of the contemporary era of competitive authoritarianism, and both attempted to overturn the result of a democratic election by inciting violence among their supporters. So why is one on trial and the other is back in power?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:31:40 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Switzerland Must Choose Press Freedom Over Bank Secrecy</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/switzerland-must-reform-article-47-banking-act-to-ensure-press-freedom-by-delphine-halgand-mishra-and-frederik-obermaier-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/switzerland-must-reform-article-47-banking-act-to-ensure-press-freedom-by-delphine-halgand-mishra-and-frederik-obermaier-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As rising geopolitical risks increasingly threaten the stability of the global financial system, investigative journalists and whistleblowers have never been more essential. But Switzerland stands in their way by criminalizing the disclosure of client data – regardless of motive or public interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 10:31:01 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Max Weber’s Lessons for Democracies Under Siege</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/max-weber-and-the-crisis-of-democracy-by-enrique-krauze-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/onpoint/max-weber-and-the-crisis-of-democracy-by-enrique-krauze-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amid the chaos of the 1918-19 Munich Revolution, the sociologist Max Weber delivered an urgent warning about the perils of demagoguery, fanaticism, and charismatic leaders who confuse conviction with sound judgment. His words fell on deaf ears then, but they remain eerily relevant.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 09:04:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Century Bonds Could Transform Development Finance</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/century-bonds-loans-instead-of-grants-to-mdbs-by-hannah-wanjie-ryder-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/century-bonds-loans-instead-of-grants-to-mdbs-by-hannah-wanjie-ryder-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If traditional donor grants have become politically toxic or financially burdensome for rich countries, why don't they instead issue 100-year, ultra-low-interest bonds to multilateral development banks? This simple idea is neither radical nor unprecedented, and it would be a game-changer for developing economies.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 13:37:29 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI Must Not Ignore Human Rights</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-ai-action-plan-no-mention-of-human-rights-by-alexandra-reeve-givens-and-karen-kornbluh-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/us-ai-action-plan-no-mention-of-human-rights-by-alexandra-reeve-givens-and-karen-kornbluh-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As US tech companies ramp up their international dealmaking, with strong backing from the Trump administration, safeguards to ensure that investments and business practices do not violate human rights are nowhere to be found. Will America abandon its core principles in the name of "winning the AI race"?&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 12:22:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The World Needs a Medical-Research Overhaul</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-south-should-be-leading-relevant-medical-research-by-sanjeev-krishna-and-jean-michel-piedagnel-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/global-south-should-be-leading-relevant-medical-research-by-sanjeev-krishna-and-jean-michel-piedagnel-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As matters stand, medical-research agendas and standards are largely dictated by funders in the Global North, even when dealing with diseases that primarily affect the Global South. This approach is not only unfair; it leads to worse health outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:41:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASEAN at a Crossroads</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/in-a-divided-world-asean-countries-refuse-to-pick-sides-by-anwar-ibrahim-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/in-a-divided-world-asean-countries-refuse-to-pick-sides-by-anwar-ibrahim-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a time of global fragmentation, ASEAN’s remarkable stability reflects its commitment to open trade, regional cooperation, and active non-alignment. By rejecting unilateral trade measures and retaliatory tariffs, the bloc offers an alternative to great-power politics and protectionism.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 09:46:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Failure of Anti-Austerity Populism</title><link>https://archive.is/o/xWwb1/https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/failure-of-anti-austerity-populism-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-09</link><guid>https://www.project-syndicate.org/commentary/failure-of-anti-austerity-populism-by-kenneth-rogoff-2025-09</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the 2008 global financial crisis, many economists embraced the argument that governments could borrow freely without long-term consequences. But post-pandemic inflation and higher interest rates have shattered that narrative, exposing anti-austerity economics for the dangerous illusion it was all along.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:47:29 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>